Bit by bit...By bit he carved a nightmare!
The Toolbox Murders is a horror, mystery, thriller
film directed by Dennis Donnelly.
A serial killer, plagued by the memory of a fatal car accident, uses various tools to murder female tenants of
a Los Angeles apartment complex, then abducts a teenaged girl who lives there with her family.
When the police express doubt that the murders are connected to the girl's
disappearance, her brother sets out to search for her on his own.
Vance Kingsley, played by Cameron Mitchell.
Laurie Ballard, played by Pamelyn Ferdin.
Kent Kingsley, played by Wesley Eure.
Joanne Ballard, played by Aneta Corsaut.
Joey Ballard, played by Nicolas Beauvy.
Detective Jamison, played by Tim Donnelly.
The Toolbox Murders is a 1978 American slasher film directed by Dennis Donnelly,
from a screenplay by Neva Friedenn, Robert Easter, and Anne Kindberg.
Starring Cameron Mitchell, Pamelyn Ferdin, and Wesley Eure, it follows a series of violent murders centered around a Los
Angeles apartment complex, followed by the kidnapping and disappearance of a teenage girl who resides there.
The film was marketed as being a dramatization of true
events, though no source can confirm this.
It was briefly banned in the early 1980s in the United
Kingdom during the "video nasty" panic.
The film explores themes of tools, murder, slasher, drill, video nasty.
The tone is intense and dark and thought_provoking.